vfs-usa.co.in 2012-03-13

# VFS

|  |  |  | 

Privacy Policy

|  |  | **Scope:** The Privacy Policy of VFS Global Services Pvt. Limited (here in after referred to as VFS Global) describes how the information furnished by you as a visa applicant and user (hereinafter referred to as “User”) is collected, used, stored, transferred and made available to VFS Global’s contracting party, affiliates, governments, law enforcement agencies, authorities and other agencies. By accepting the Privacy Policy and user agreement, User expressly consents to our Privacy Policy.   
---|---  
| **Information Collection:** All information, posted, furnished and submitted by a user or users while scheduling an interview appointment online is converted into such formats as may be required and communicated to the US Embassy/Consulate in India (the “Embassy/Consulate”). The information so collected may be stored, transferred and shared by VFS Global , or any of its affiliated agencies, partners and any law enforcement agencies as would be required under law and mentioned herein. VFS Global may collectAll information furnished by User, and identifiable by the passport number, portal, server, I.P address etc., which is traceable in relation to VFS Global site or in relation thereto, such as IP address, E-mail address, contact detail information and other information like transactional information of User’s online usage, IP address, log-on information and standard web log information etc.   
| **Purpose of Collection:** The predominant purpose in collecting, storing, transferring or sharing the information is to: and generally to provide and communicate any of the above to our contracting party, affiliate/s, principal, governments, law enforcement agencies, authorities and other agencies to respond to legal requirements, protect any one’s right, property, safety or, allegation of fraud, misuse, abuse, mischievous intent or investigations.   
| **Cookies:** VFS Global uses "cookies" (small files placed on User’s hard drive) on certain pages of the Site to help analyze VFS Global ’s web page flow, customize our services, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety. 

**A few important things User should know about cookies are that:**

|  |  VFS Global offers certain features that are only available through the use of cookies.   
---|---  
|  VFS Global uses cookies to help identify User and maintain their signed-in status.   
|  Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted from User’s hard drive at the end of a session.   
|  User is always free to decline VFS Global ’s cookies if their browser permits, although doing so may interfere with User’s use of the site.   
|  User may encounter cookies from any links or third parties on certain pages of the site that VFS Global does not control. For example, if User views a VFS Global page created by another user, there may be a "cookie" placed by that VFS Global page. VFS Global and its contracting parties, principals, affiliate/s, among others, do not tolerate spam. A user/users is/are not licensed, permitted, expected to add, modify, deface, hack, misuse or abuse VFS Global’s website or the contents therein. To report any issues related to spam or spoof emails to VFS Global , please address emails to [infousmumbai@vfshelpline.com](mailto:infousmumbai@vfshelpline.com) User may not use VFS Global ’s communication tools or webpage to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our user agreement. VFS Global filters and automatically scans messages for viruses and other illegal or prohibited content before they are sent. VFS Global does not permanently store email messages sent to or by it through various formats. VFS Global does not rent or sell any email addresses to third parties.   
  
| **User Account Information, Password & Personal Information:** User’s passport, fee receipt number, date of birth and name are key to User’s account. User is advised to exercise caution in disclosing User’s information and not to disclose the same to anyone. If User shares his/her password or personal information with others, User will be solely responsible for all actions taken in the name of User’s account. If User loses control of the same, User may lose substantial control over User’s personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions for actions taken on through their account or on User’s behalf. Therefore, if User’s password or personal information has been compromised for any reason, User should immediately notify VFS Global and ensure appropriate safety and security measures.   
| **Accessing, Reviewing & Modifying Personal and Other Information:** User can see, review and change most of their personal information by logging into the site. Generally, VFS Global will not manually modify a user’s personal information because it is very difficult to verify any user’s identity or other details. User must promptly update User’s personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. Once User submits any information, they will be able to change or remove it only up to 48 hours before the time and date of the interview. VFS Global retains personal information of users in order to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce the terms and conditions and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.   
| **Security:** User’s information is stored on VFS Global’s servers located in India . VFS Global treats data as an asset that must be protected and uses tools like encryption, passwords, physical security, firewalls, and other security features and measures to protect its website and users personal information against unauthorized disclosure, access, misuse, abuse, hacking etc. However, sometimes third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse or misuse a user’s/users’ personal information that they may collect from the website. 

Therefore, although VFS works very hard to protect users’ privacy, it cannot guarantee User that personal information or private communications will always remain private and secure.   
  
| **General:** The contents of this Privacy Policy may be changed at any time and User will be subject to terms as applicable at the time of usage.  
  
Copyright 2012. VFS Global. All Rights Reserved. User Terms and conditions, Privacy Policy  
  
| 

VISA APPLICATION  
PROCESS

|  | Determine your consular district and [visa type](http://travel.state.gov/visa/temp/types/types_1286.html).  
---|---  
|   
| Obtain a photo that can be uploaded and meets form specifications.  
|   
| Access the form DS-160. Complete your DS-160 application online. Save often to your desktop! Answer questions as thoroughly as possible before submitting, as incomplete forms may not be accepted.  
|   
| Print the DS-160 barcode confirmation sheet at the end of the DS-160 application on a laser printer. After you have printed it, email the confirmation page to yourself so you have a backup copy. The file is a PDF file, so Adobe you will need Adobe Acrobat on your computer to open it.  
|   
| Pay the visa application fee at an approved HDFC bank.   
|   
| Make your appointment using your barcode number and fee receipt. If appropriate, use the “coworkers/family members traveling together” option. Then, download and print your VFS appointment letter.  
|   
| For Mumbai district applicants only: Drop off your required documents three working days prior to your appointment at a VFS center in Mumbai, Pune or Ahmedabad.  
|   
| For H (H-1B, H-3, H-4) and L (L-1, L-2) visa applicants applying at the Hyderabad Consulate General only: ** ** Applicants must submit documents only four working days in advance of their visa appointment date and if they wish to submit documents earlier it must not be more than five working days in advance of the visa appointment date at the VFS center in Hyderabad (in person only). There will be no exceptions to this rule. You may also take the help of a representative acting on your behalf, to submit the documents. **** Please visit the website [http://hyderabad.usconsulate  
.gov/advance _doc_submission2.html](http://hyderabad.usconsulate.gov/advance_doc_submission2.html)   
for information on the required documents. (Please note that BEP H and L visa applicants should follow the BEP procedure for the Hyderabad Consulate General.)  
|   
| Report for your interview at the U.S. Embassy or Consulate fifteen minutes before your appointment. Carry appropriate documents and follow security regulations. All applicants can find a list of documents under their visa type in the All About Visas - Non-Immigrant Visas section.   
|   
| Approved visas are returned by courier. Click here to track your passport.
